

Ana Margarida Silva ams-amargarida @hotmail.com (+351) 918246437

Personal Pages github.com/BeeMargarida linkedin.com/in/anamargarida-silva/ gitlab.com/BeeMargarida

Address

Rua Bouça da Cavadinha 182, HAB933 3ºDT, São Mamede de Infesta 4465-005 São Mamede de Infesta Portugal

Ana Margarida Silva

Student of Masters Degree in Informatics and Computing Engineering

About Me My name is Ana Margarida Silva and I am currently in the last year of a five year degree Masters in Informatics and Computing Engineering. My main interests consist of developing my skills in my field of study, by learning new technologies and expanding my knowledge, and extracurricular activities such as music. My current goals consist of finishing my degree, learning more about the programming history and best pratices.

Education

2004-2015, Agrupamento de Escolas do Búzio Primary and high school

2015-2020, Faculty of Engineering of the University of Porto Masters Degree in Informatics and Computing Engineering

Experience

September 2019 - Present, Junior Software Engineer, Platforme

Work on the RIPE technology stack, that includes both core services and client-facing interfaces. Use of technologies like Python, Node.JS, Type-Script and Vue.js/React.js.

2015 - 2020, Student of Masters Degree in Informatics and Computing Engineering, FEUP

Final grade: 16.4

• *Masters Thesis in* Orchestration for Automatic Decentralization in Visually-defined IoT - Development of a prototype, extending from Node-RED, that enables the automatic decentralization of an IoT system. The devices in the network communicate their computational capabilities to the orchestrator, which is responsible for automatically partition the computation and sending the generated tasks to the devices, leveraging their computational power. Final grade: 20

October 2019 - September 2020, Software Engineer Trainee - Part-Time, Platforme

Work in several projects, including back-end and core services using Python and Node.JS, front-end interfaces using Vue.js/React.js to client side tools using Javascript.

"The Web Developer Bootcamp" course

Completion of an online course, from Udemy, that teaches full stack web developing. It includes technologies like HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB and others.



Ana Margarida Silva ams-amargarida @hotmail.com (+351) 918246437

Personal Pages github.com/BeeMargarida linkedin.com/in/anamargarida-silva/ gitlab.com/BeeMargarida

> Address Rua Bouça da Cavadinha 182, HAB933 3°DT, São

Mamede de Infesta 4465-005 São Mamede de Infesta Portugal

July 2018 - September 2018, Summer Internship at Blip

During the summer of 2018, I made an internship at Blip, a company that is a part of the group PaddyPower Betfair. The goal of the internship was the development of a Web App with technologies like React, Apache Kafka and Betfair's Cougar framework.

Personal Skills

Mother tongue

Portuguese

Other languages

• CAE (Certificate in Advanced English) exam - grade A

Language	Understanding	Reading	Writing
English	Very Good	Very Good	Good
Spanish	Good	Good	Moderate

Communication skills

- Frequent team work and presentations during the several projects of the masters degree.
- Presentation and introduction of several musical performances.

Other skills and occupations

- Bass guitar player in "Orquestra Ligeira de Cambra".
- Clarinet player in "Sociedade Artística Banda de Vale de Cambra".
- Member of the board of the "Orquestra Ligeira de Cambra" and "Sociedade Artística Banda de Vale de Cambra".

Software Development Skills

Programming Languages, Technologies and Frameworks

 Javascript 	Python	NodeJS
VueJS	o C++	• C
o CSS3	o HTML5	Java
MongoDB	 PostgreSQL 	MySQL
o Linux	ReactJS	• React Native
Docker	o CI/CD	Scrum

Awards

2015, *Best High School Student*, Rotary Club de Vale de Cambra Awarded to the top student in their final year of high school.

2015, *Board of Excellence*, Agrupamento de Escolas do Búzio Awarded to the top students in their final year of high school and elementary school.



Ana Margarida Silva ams-amargarida @hotmail.com (+351) 918246437

Personal Pages github.com/BeeMargarida linkedin.com/in/anamargarida-silva/ gitlab.com/BeeMargarida

> Address Rua Bouça da Cavadinha 182, HAB933 3°DT, São Mamede de Infesta 4465-005 São Mamede de Infesta Portugal

Interests

Professional
Web development, Cyber Security, Software Development
Personal
Bass Guitar, Clarinet, Music, Reading